Negotiation
20th December - 11:50 am
You over there.
君
Yes?
はい？
The truth is, I actually came to Japan on a top secret mission, so if you could refrain from mentioning to the Japanese police that... err..
実は…私は極秘の捜査で日本に来ていて
日本の警察には、あ、その…
I understand.
わかりました
I won't tell anyone that I've met you... including my father.
あなたに会ったことは誰にも言いません
勿論父にも…
In that case, I'd better get going.
じゃあ、私はここで…
It's just as I thought.
思った通りだ…
I don't want anyone to know that I've encountered the FBI either.
僕だって、 FBI 捜査官と接触したなんて、警察に知られたくない
If my father were to find out, L would definitely be informed.
父に知らせるは、必ず L に伝わる
He doesn't even suspect me slightly, and now this incident will be dismissed as a mere accident by the police.
彼は僕をまったく疑ってない
今ここで起きたことは、警察にただの事故として処理される
Welcome home.
お帰り
Yeah, I'm back.
ああ、ただいま
What's up? What's with the big sigh?
どうしたの？大きな溜め息
Did something happen, Ray?
何があった、レイ
Yeah, I was caught up in a random bus hi-jacking.
ああ、偶然バスジャックに巻き込まれた
A bus hi-jack?
バスジャック？
A criminal, who attempted to rob a bank two days ago, decided to try his luck at a bus hi-jacking this time.
二日前、銀行襲った犯人が、今度はバスジャックさ
Japan's a scary place these days...
日本も恐い国になったものだ
And you just happened to be on that bus?
そのバスにあなたも乗り合わせたって事？
Yeah.
ああ
In the end, the culprit jumped off the bus and ended up being hit by an oncoming car.
結局犯人は、バスを飛び降りて、車にはねられたけどね
That culprit... did he die?
その犯人…死んだの？
I think so...
多分な…
I didn't have time to see things right through to the end though.
見届ける暇はなかった
Ray...
ねぇ、レイ
What if that wasn't just a coincidence?
それって、本当に偶然だったのかしら？
What do you mean?
どういうことだ？
I mean... you were investigating someone when you got on that bus, right?
だって、誰かを調べていて、そのバスに乗ったんでしょ？
And somehow, a criminal has ended up dead.
そこで、犯罪者が恐らく死んだ
That's...
それって…
Hey, I know that you were a brilliant FBI investigator, but right now, you're just my fiancée.
なぁ…
君は確かに優秀な FBI 捜査官だった
しかし今は、僕のフィアンセでしかない
You've got to remember that you're no longer an investigator.
もう君が捜査官じゃないんだ
"I won't get involved in the Kira-case."
「キラ事件には口を出さない」、
"I won't do anything dangerous."
「危険な行動はとらない」
You promised me those things before coming here, and that's why I brought you with me, so we can visit your parents in Japan.
そういう約束で、
日本にいる君の両親に挨拶する為に一緒に連れてきたんだ
I know, Ray. It's just a habit.. I'm sorry.
わかったわ、レイ
つい癖で…ごめんなさい
I know, Ray. It's just a habit.. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Sorry, you don't need to worry about it that much.
ああ、ごめん、そんなに気にするなよ
Once we start a family, you'll be too busy to remember what it was like to be an investigator.
家族ができれば、
自分が捜査官だった事を忘れる位、忙しくなって
You won't have the time to slip into old habits.
癖なんて出る暇も無くなってしまうさ
More importantly, you've got to help me think of a way to impress your dad.
それより…
あのお父さんに　なんて挨拶したら好感度が上がるか、考えてくれよ
Huh?
おお、早速昼間突き止めた捜査官の名前を書くってわけか…
You gonna write the name of the agent you've just identified?
Not yet. It'll be a week before I'll write his name.
いや、彼の名前を書くのは一週間後だ
If he were to die immediately after encountering me, it'd look suspicious.
会ってすぐ彼が死ねば、僕に疑いがかかる
It's better for me to wait till his investigation progresses further, and allow him the opportunity to investigate as many people connected to the police as possible.
もっと彼らの捜査が進んで、
より多くの警察関係者が調べられてからの方がいい
For the time being, I'll bait L with some more prisoners...
暫くはまた、刑務所内の犯罪者を使って、 L の相手さ
L, there's been another victim that's left some sort of suicide note.
L
また遺書のようなものを書き残した犠牲者が出ました
Send me the images.
画像を送ってくれ
Shinigami...
「死神は…」
L, did you know
「 L、知っているか」　「死神は…」
Shinigami...
Are you trying to tell me that Shinigami actually exist?
死神が存在するとでも言いたいのか
Watari, tell the police to continue surveying the prisons.
ワタリ、刑務所から目を離さないよう、警察に伝えてくれ
We may see more prisoners leaving notes behind.
これからも何か書き残すものが出るかもしれない
Understood.
わかりました
27th December - 3:00 pm
Wow, it's pretty busy around here.
すごい人間の数だな
Is this where it's going to happen?
ここでやるのか
Finally I'll be able to show you the results of the investigations and experiments I've been carrying out these past few days.
この数日間調べた事と…
色んな実験をした成果を見せてやるよ
Experiments?
実験？
Yeah.
ああ、まだデスノートを使い、
With the aid of the Death Note, I've been able to identify several different methods of killing people by utilizing some of the local criminals as my test subjects.
この辺一帯の犯罪者で、色んな殺し方を検証をしてみた
Accidental Death
26th December              8:30 pm
Run over by a car.
If the cause of death and any further details are written in the Death Note first, and the name is added afterwards...
デスノートは死因や死の状況を先に書き、
Hanekuroda
後から名前を書き込めば、その通りになるんだ
That person will still die exactly as it is written.
Eeh? Even I hadn't realized that...
へぇ
俺も知らない事を…
He's here.
来た
Right on time.
時間通りだ
Ray Penber-san.
レイ．ペンバーさん
Turn around, and I'll kill you.
振り向いたら殺します
I'm Kira.
キラです
If you even think about turning around or putting your hands in your pockets I'll kill you instantly.
振り向いたり、ポケットに手を入れたりしたら、
その瞬間に殺します
This can't be real!
ま、まさか…
But wait... This voice... I've heard it before.. somewhere...
しかしこの声…何処かで…
First, I'll prove to you that I am Kira.
まず、キラだと言う証拠を見せます
You see that cafe over there?
いま、あなたから見える喫茶店、
There's a guy wearing glasses working there. I'm going to kill him.
あそこで働いている、眼鏡を掛けた男を殺します
Y-You're kidding?!
ば…馬鹿な
Don't do it!
やめろ！
I thought that I should at least kill one person for you to take me seriously.
最低一人は殺してみせないと、
信じて戴けないと思ったので…仕方ありません
It couldn't be helped.
That man has a record of physically abusing women, but due to lack of evidence he's never been convicted for it.
しかしあの男は、婦女暴行を数件くり返しながら、
証拠不十分で警察が起訴できなかった
It's only right that those who cause suffering to society should receive judgement.
裁きを受けて当然の社会悪です
I'm sure that L's told you that I'm only able to kill people if I know their faces.
もう L などから聞いて知っていると思いますが…
私は殺そうと思う者の顔が判らなければ、殺せません
To put it simply, I can kill anyone who's around us.
逆に、ここから見える全ての人間を殺せるということです
If you've got any requests, just go ahead and ask. I'll kill them.
リクエストなら殺します…
S-Stop!
や…止めろ…
I believe that you're Kira.
キラだと言うことを信じる
In any case, I'm sure that it'd be much more painful for you to lose someone dear to you than to lose anyone here.
もっとも、あなたにとってはここにいる人達よりも…
自分の大切な人の命を奪われるの方が…辛いでしょ
I'd like you to consider that person as the one really being held hostage here.
今人質にされているのは…そちらだと思ってください
Impossible! Not her...
ま…まさか、彼女を…
That's correct. I've done some research on you.
そうです、あなたのことは調べました
If you go against any of my orders, I'll kill everyone. Including your family.
少しでも私の指示と異なる行動を取ったら、
あなたの家族も含め、皆殺します
And of course you.
勿論あなたも
わ…わかった、私にどうしようと…
I understand. What do you want from me?
I take it you've brought your laptop with you?
パソコンは持ってきましたね
Do you have all the files of all the investigators assigned to Japan on it?
そのパソコンには…
日本に入ったその捜査官のファイルは…入っていますか？
Going to work, I've always got my laptop with me, but I don't have any of those files.
ノートパソコンは…仕事柄いつも持ち歩いている
しかしそんなファイルは入っていない
Then, please take this envelope.
では、この封筒をどうぞ
おお？
First, take out the transceiver and put the ear piece on.
まず、中に入っているトランシーバーを出して、
イヤホーンをつけて下さい
A transceiver? This is practically a toy...
トランシーバー…しかも玩具に近い
Yet, this way, there'll be no record of communication, and even underground, as long as we're close enough, we'll be able to talk.
だが、これだら通信記録はどこにも残らないし、
地下であろうと、近距離ならば会話ができる、考えたら…
He's thought this through...
Next, please get on the Yamanote line.
それでは、山手線に乗って下さい
I don't care whether you take the inside or the outside track.
内回り外回り、どちらでも構いません
I'll be constantly observing you from a distance.
私は常に、少し離れたところであなたを監視しています
Even while you are on the train, look straight ahead.
電車に乗っても前だけ、一点を見ていてください
Please remember that I can kill you at any time.
いつでも殺せると言うことを忘れないように…
Once you've boarded, sit at a corner seat by the door.
乗ったら、ドアに近い隅の席に座ってください
If there isn't one free, we'll wait until there is one.
空いてがなければ、空くまで待ちましょう
I'm going to ask you several questions.
まずお聞きします
If I get an answer that completely conflicts with my expectations, I'll kill your girlfriend.
私の見解とまったく違う答えが帰ってきたら、
あなたと彼女を殺します
How many FBI agents have entered Japan, and how are they organized?
日本に入った FBI の編制と人数は…
Answer quietly into the transceiver.
トランシーバーで、小声て答えて下さい
I heard that there are twelve of us, divided into four teams.
四チーム、合計十二人と聞いている…
In that case, take out the contents of the envelope.
では、封筒の中の物を出してください
What the hell... is this?
なんだ、これは…
I'd like you to write the name of your direct superior, who should have all the names of the investigators, in the top box.
ではその捜査官の内、
メンバー全員を把握している、あなたの直接の上司の名前を、
一番上の穴に書いてください
What's going on? What's he trying to do?
どういうことだ…
何が狙いだ…
But right now, I've got no choice but to do as he says.
しかし、今は言う通りにするしかない…
If he only has their names, he shouldn't be able to kill them.
名前だけなら、まだ殺せないはずだ
Next, I'd like you to open up your laptop.
次にパソコンを開いてください
Your superior should be sending you some files soon.
もうすぐあなたの上司から、ファイルが送られてきます
They should be the files containing the names and faces of all FBI agents that have entered Japan.
日本に入った FBI 全員の、顔と名前を入ったファイルです
W-What's this?
こ、これは…
Like before, I want you to write each name in a box while concentrating on each of their faces.
それでは、先程と同じように、
捜査官一人一人の名前を、
よく顔を見ながら、封筒に記入してください
I don't get it.
わからない…キラは、何をしようとしている
Kira, what are you trying to do?
What are you doing?
何をしている…
Seems like you've finished your work.
作業は終わったようですね
Please place the papers and the transceiver back into the original envelope, and leave it on the wire rack.
では元の封筒に、トランシーバーと、
名前を書いた封筒を入れて、網棚に載せ
Once you've done that, remain on the train for a further 30 minutes without moving.
三十分以上を、身動きせずにこの電車に乗り続け
Then, once you're sure that no one will notice you leaving the envelope, disembark the train at a station.
その封筒を忘れている事に、
誰も気付かない状況だと判断できた駅で、
電車から降りてください
Why... why can't I remember whose voice this is?
何故だ…何故あの声の主思い出せない
4:41 pm
キラ、お前は一体…
Kira!
What on earth are you?
Yagami... Light!
夜神…月…！
Goodbye... Ray Penber.
さよなら、レイ．ペンバー…
The papers Ray Penber wrote on were torn out pages from the Death Note.
レイ．ペンバーが名前を記入したのは、
切り取ったデスノート…
Basically, he killed his own teammates without even realizing it.
彼も知らず知らずのうちに、自分の仲間を殺したことになる
Penber's superior died after sending the files to all members of the team.
ペンバーの上司は、捜査官全員にファイルを送った後に死亡
All the investigators on the team died of a heart attack after receiving those files.
残りの捜査官たちも全員…ファイルをもらった後に心臓麻痺
L, you've got a call from the Director of the FBI.
L、 FBI 長官から連絡が入っています
私だ…
It's me.
I've just heard that all our investigators that we sent to Japan have been found dead.
日本から、捜査官全員の死亡したとの知らせが入った…
All of them died of a heart attack.
全て心臓麻痺、キラに殺されたとしか思えない
I can only assume that they must have been killed by Kira.
I'm sorry to have to do this, L, but we're going to have to cut off our investigations in Japan.
申しわけないが、 L
我々 FBI は…日本での捜査を打ち切る
I'm sorry to have to do this, L, but we're going to have to cut off our investigations in Japan.
Chief Yagami is on the line for you.
夜神局長からです
L, I've just spoken to the Director of the FBI.
L 、今 FBI 長官と話したところです
It seems that you've been using the FBI to investigate us and those who are connected with us.
それによると、あなたは FBI に、
我々捜査本部の関係者を洗わせていたようですが…
Yes.
はい
What is the meaning of this?
どういうことです
あなたは我々を疑っていると…
Do you mean to say that you actually suspected us?
I decided that it was a necessity in order to narrow down Kira's identity.
キラの正体に迫る為に…必要だと判断しました
納得できません！
This is unacceptable!
You can't treat your allies as spies!
仲間であるはずの我々に対して、そんなスパイ紛いなことを…
I guess we can't trust L after all.
L …やはり信用できないな
But this means that Kira must have killed FBI agents too.
それよりキラは、 FBI も殺したって事だろう
Kira will kill anyone who opposes them, even if the person isn't a criminal.
自分に楯突く者は、犯罪者でなくとも殺す
Kira is a real monster!
本当の殺人鬼じゃないか、キラは
There's another prisoner who has left a suicide note.
また文書を残した犠牲者が…
L 、知っているか？
L, did you know?
Shinigami..
死神は…
only eat apples
リンゴしか食べない
キラめ…
Damn you, Kira!
He's dead.
死んだ…
Ray is..
レイが…
No! He was killed by Kira.
いえ…キラに殺された…
What's this "family meeting" about?
なぁに？家族会議って…
Even if I tried to hide it, you'd all eventually find out, so I'll tell you now.
隠していてもいずれわかることだ…ここで言っておく
I'm currently heading the investigation into Kira.
私は今、キラ事件の捜査本部の指揮を取る立場にある
そうなんだ～やっぱ凄いねお父さんって
Really? Wow, you're really amazing, dad!
いや、本題はここからだ
That's just the start of my problems.
Huh?
ん？
To tell you the truth, yesterday, twelve FBI agents that were sent to Japan to investigate Kira.. all died.
実は昨日…
キラを見つけ出す為に日本に入った FBI の者十二人…
To tell you the truth, yesterday, twelve FBI agents that were sent to Japan to investigate Kira.. all died.
全員が亡くなった
You mean they were all killed by Kira?
キラに殺されたって事か？
へぇ？
つまり…キラを捕まえようとするものは、
殺されるかもしれない
And to put it bluntly, if I go after Kira, I may die.
It's the most horrific crime I've ever seen.
嘗てない恐ろしい犯罪だ…辞めていく部下も多い
A lot of my staff are leaving.
お…お父さんも辞めろよ
You should quit as well, dad.
父さんが死んじゃったら嫌だ
I don't want you to die!
そうよ、立場とかより命が大切よ
She's right. Your life is far more important than your job!
No. There's no way I'm stepping down from this case.
いや、私は絶対この事件から降りない
悪に屈してはならない
We must not bow to evil.
お父さん…
Dad...
あなた…
Dear...
I think that's very honorable of you, father. I'm very proud of you.
立派だよ、父さん
僕は父さんを…誇りに思う
父さんにもしもの事があったら…
But if anything happens to you... I'll make sure that Kira will be sentenced to death!
必ず僕が…キラを死刑台に送る
Kira is willing to kill those who oppose them even if they aren't criminals.
キラは、犯罪者でくとも、自分に逆らう者は殺す
We could all be killed.
我々はキラに殺されるかもしれない…
自分の人生、家族、友の事を考えるんだ
I'd like you to think of your lives, families and friends.
この捜査から外れたい者は、外れてくれ
Anyone who wants to leave is free to do so.
外れても降格などはない…約束しよう
I promise you there'll be no risk of demotion.
Only those of you who have the conviction to fight Kira, even if you have to sacrifice all the things I've just mentioned, should stay.
私が挙げた事を犠牲にしてても…
キラと戦おうという信念のあるものだけ残ってくれ
Only those of you who have the conviction to fight Kira, even if you have to sacrifice all the things I've just mentioned, should stay.
That is all.
以上だ
おい　どうする？
What should we do?
ああ…
Yes, yes. That's him.
ああそうそう、この人だ
I remember him telling everyone to get down.
「伏せろ」って言ったから憶えてるよ
しかし他の客まではちょっと…
But I don't remember the rest of the passengers.
Is that so? I understand. Thank you.
そうですか…わかりました
ありがとうございます
Is that so? I understand. Thank you.
私の考えていることが正しければ…
If my thinking is correct... Kira may have been among those passengers.
その乗客の中にキラがいたかも知れない…
だとすれば…このバスを利用できる沿線にキラが…
In that case, I should be able to use this bus as a route to get to Kira.
五人か…
Five, huh?
私を入れて六人…
Six people, including myself.
いや、六人も命を張って悪に立ち向かう者がいたと考えよう
No. In fact, I'd like to think of it as six people willing to stand up to evil.
I'm willing to trust the six of you who have shown yourselves to have a great sense of justice.
私は強い正義感を持ったあなた方こそを信じます
Wait a second!
ちょっと待ってくれ
L may have just said that he trusts us, but we don't trust L!
L は今私たちを信じると言ったが…
我々は L を信用していない
L may have just said that he trusts us, but we don't trust L!
L 、我々は命懸けでキラを捕まえると決心した
L, we've all decided to put our lives on the line to catch Kira.
キラに対して、命を掛ける意味は分かっているはずだ
You should know what that means!
Yet you've only ever given orders without revealing your face.
しかしあなたはいつも顔を見せず、我々に指示するだけ
そんな人間と行動を共にすることなど…できない
We can't work with someone like that!
L, if you're serious about joining forces with us to catch Kira, will you come here and join us?
L …もし私たちと力を合わせ、
キラを捕まえる気持ちがあるのなら…
あなたもここへ来てくれないか？
L, if you're serious about joining forces with us to catch Kira, will you come here and join us?
I just said that I would trust you.
私は先程は…あなた方を信用すると言いました
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I would like the following
events to be kept a secret
between the eight of us.
I'd like to meet you six, trustworthy people
as soon as possible.
But before that,
I want you to leave
the building and
discuss whether
you choose to
trust me or not.
Why is he asking for our support now, at the risk of exposing himself?
何故今更たった六人に協力を仰ぐ
They say that he's solved countless cases on his own.
今まで、いくつもの難事件を一人で解決してきたというなら…
He should be able to solve this one on his own too.
今回も一人でやればいい
それに、 L の今までのやり口だと、
Besides, judging by his past actions, we may end up dealing with a fake.
我々が会うのは L ではなく、影武者かも知れないだろ
A fake, huh? Could be possible...
影武者が…あり得るな
I-I want to trust L.
ぼ…僕は L を信用します
I believe that L's skills will be invaluable to us in this case.
それに、この事件には L の力が必要だと思います
Me too.
私も…
L は始めから、
L's said from the start that this case would require the cooperation of the police.
この事件には、警察の力が必要だと言っていた
こうは考えられないか
Isn't it conceivable that... L was actually waiting for this to happen?
L はこうなる事を待っていた…
"For this to happen"?
こうなる事…？
捜査本部には、始めからL に不信感を持つ者がいた
There were people on the case, right from the start, who were suspicious of L.
People were resigning left, right and center, and information was somehow being leaked.
次々に辞表を出すものも出てきた…
そして、内部情報の漏れ、これでは信用して指揮は取れない
It would have been impossible for him to command the investigation with trust.
You mean L's been waiting until only those dedicated individuals he could trust, and whom are willing to stand against evil remained at headquarters?
つまり、本部の人間が、死を恐れず悪に立ち向かう
L の信用できる人間だけになる事を…待っていたと…
Either way, if you're going to join forces with L, I quit.
とにかく、 L と組むなら、私は降ります
Don't worry. I won't try to follow any of you, or try to find L.
安心してください
皆をつけたり、 L を探そうなど事は、しませんから
私は L を信用し、協力してやってみます
I choose to trust L and work alongside him.
Me too.
…私も
I'm currently in a room at the Teitou hotel.
私は今、帝東ホテルの一室にいます
I'll be switching between hotels in the city every few days.
これから数日おきに、都内のホテルを移動します
今後はこのホテルの部屋を、事実上の捜査本部として戴きたい
I'd like to request that my hotel room be used as the real headquarters during this investigation.
If you agree to these stipulations, I'd like you to split into two groups, and, leaving a gap of at least 30 minutes between the two, come up to my room before midnight.
この条件で協力して頂けるなら、
二組に分れ、三十分以上の間を空けて、
午前零時までに…ここに来て戴きたい
Kira, right now it seems that we are moving towards each other at an even rate.
キラ…
あえて現時点でのお互いまでの距離は…
Kira, right now it seems that we are moving towards each other at an even rate.
イーブンで縮まってると考えよう
いいだろう…私は始めて、
Alright then.
I'll expose myself as L, in front of people, for the first time.
L として人前に姿を現そう
If you find out about this, I can guarantee that you'll try to move in on me.
もしお前がこの事を知ることができたなら…
必ずお前をは接近してくる
Bring it on!
望むところだ…
I've done quite a lot over the last few days...
僕はこの数日…かなり動いた
I've got to think hard.
考えるんだ、落ち度はなかったか…
Did I make any mistakes?
そして、これからどう行動するか…
How should I proceed from here?
The real battle starts now, L!
これからが本当の戦いだ… L
Please come in.
どうぞ、お入りください
To be continued
この女が…僕より先に警察に話していたら…
しかし、どうやら死神じゃない方の神は…
僕の味方らしい